# **David Michalek**

2139 S L Street Tacoma, WA 98405 425-553-9907 David3893@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/dmichalek/

Motivated self-driven engineer and manager with 6+ years of experience in networking, QA, and mobility/telecom. Proven track record in providing leadership, attention to detail, and technical expertise to deliver quality business products. Possesses an associate degree in Information Technology and bachelor's degree in Cybersecurity.

## Leadership Skills

#### SDLC Management • QA Methodologies and Leadership • Automation Implementation

- QA Service Lead Full software development lifecycle experience from lab to launch; focused on test-driven development, including test plan design/development/execution. Experience interfacing with business to business enterprise partners including device manufacturers and software developers.
- <u>Subject Matter Expert</u> QA testing and Push-to-Talk domains, playing an integral role in project-based solutions as a key participant in requirements definition, systems design review, and validation efforts by leading user-acceptance testing.
- <u>Full Lifecycle Support</u> Post launch, leading test efforts of new releases and providing Tier 4 support that addresses complex, customer-facing production issues. Experience coordinating disparate internal and external teams to drive corrective action. Provide on-site support for key customers or high impact issues.
- <u>Customer Advocate</u> User focused, translating real-world feedback and experiences into processes
  that drive positive changes to the solution in support of the end-user.

### **Technical Proficiencies**

#### Full Network Deployments • Detail Oriented Troubleshooting • Scripting Efficiencies

- Platforms: FirstNet, AT&T Commercial Network, iOS, Android, Windows Server, Linux/Unix
- Programming/Scripting: Python, Bash, Power Shell, HTML, Javascript, CSS, SQL
- System Implementation: switches, routers, servers, desktops, and storage
- Troubleshooting: Wireshark, ADB, IrisView, Splunk
- Lifecycle Management: HP ALM Server, JIRA, TDP
- Security Tools: Kali Linux, IDS/IPS, Microsoft Threat Modeling Tool

# **Professional Experience**

## Service Lead – New Product/Technology Development

Mobile Integration Workgroup, Inc. at AT&T Redmond, WA

March 2018-Present

- Helped develop and implement multiple troubleshooting processes that saved over \$5 million in corporate funding
- Discovered and helped drive resolution of a security risk that saved potentially \$10-20 million and impacting millions of clients
- Managed automation project to improve testing efforts

## **Quality Assurance Manager**

Vimro, LLC. at AT&T Redmond, WA

March 2016-March 2018

- Managed technical staff: scope of work, resource allocation, employee growth
- Hired and trained technical staff to support multiple platforms
- Produced team schedule and delegated tasks
- Reported metrics of progress and defect burndown to leadership

# **David Michalek**

2139 S L Street Tacoma, WA 98405 425-553-9907 David3893@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/dmichalek/

## Senior Quality Assurance Engineer

Vimro, LLC. at AT&T Redmond, WA

July 2015-March 2016

- Deployed and supported communication platform of a first-responder network
- Performed end-to-end mobile network traceroutes to support multiple cloud services
- Investigated on-site customer issues for public safety
- Executed nationwide LTE and satellite testing for a Push-to-Talk service

## Quality Assurance Engineer

Vimro, LLC. at AT&T Redmond, WA

July 2014-July 2015

- Created test object lists that were tailored to user experience
- Conducted manual testing: iOS, Android, Windows PC, and embedded devices
- Managed defects and worked closely with developers to resolve app issues

### Network Administrator

BluZebra Technologies, Inc. Seattle, WA

December 2013-July 2014

- Setup, install, configured, and supported small-medium business networks including switches, servers, firewalls, and desktops
- Monitored and implemented maintenance activities to ensure QoS for clients
- Created test matrices and action plans to deploy what was best for the client.
- Improved efficiencies on tasks by scripting/automating using Bash/PowerShell/etc.

# Volunteer Experience

## Software Developer

UW Tacoma Giving Garden, Tacoma, WA

March 2019-August 2019

- Developed a prototype for a fully autonomous, self-sustaining irrigation system
- Configured a Raspberry Pi that was powered by a solar panel and water supply from a rain barrel
- Created scripts with Python and Bash for feature-set including automated watering schedule, check weather, time-lapse photos/video, and a daily health check email
- Setup the Raspberry Pi to act as a Wi-Fi AP and which could be managed using a web interface via any mobile device in the vicinity

### **Penetration Tester**

Workforce Central, Tacoma, WA

September 2019-December 2019

- Performed a Security Risk Analysis
- Delivered a Risk Assessment Report to help leadership spread information security awareness
- Presented along with drafting a contract/scope of work for my team
- Utilized a multitude of pen testing tools within Kali Linux
- Gave a follow-up presentation to their staff regarding best practices of security awareness

## **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

GREEN RIVER COLLEGE

June 2016

Associate of Applied Science - IT Systems

University of Washington

June 2020

Bachelor of Applied Science – IT Cybersecurity

Certifications

CompTIA Network+

CompTIA Security+

MTA – Security MTA – Networking



